Register to The Karl Weigl Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, Series I
  - Music By Others, I.B
    - [Kinderstücke] Sechs Kinderstücke: für Klavier / von Paul Frankl., Frankl, Paul; 1 manuscript score ([27] p.); 34 cm. (Box 22, Folder 552)
      Undated manuscript score, possibly by a copyist.
      Inscribed to Vally Weigl, 1926 Aug 1.
    - [Trio, piano, strings, op.1] Wien: Universal Edition, c1910., Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957; 1 score (51 p.); 32 cm. (Box 22, Folder 553)
      Plate no.: U.E.2766.
    - Rondo capriccioso: op. 14 / Felix Meldelssohn [i.e. Mendelssohn]-Bartholdy; arr. by Chas J. Roberts. New York; Carl Fischer, c1919., Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847; 1 piano score (12 p.); 31 cm. (Box 22, Folder 554)
      Originally for piano solo; arr. for orchestra.
      "Piano-conductor score".
      Plate no.: 21384-65.
    - [Symphonische Gesänge] Leipzig: Max Brockhaus, n.d., Polsterer, Rudolf; 1 score (23 p.); 34 cm. (Box 22, Folder 555)
      Plate no.: M.B.663a-M.B.663f.
    - Songs of Alexias: for baritone and piano: op. 119 / Klaus Roy, August, 1982; [texts from] Mary Renault, "The Last of the Wine," 1956., Roy, Klaus George, 1924-2010; 1 manuscript score (20 p.); 32 cm. (Box 22, Folder 556)
      "To the memory of John W. Weigl."
      Duration: 17'-18'.
      Photocopy of a holograph score dated 1982 Sep 3-5.
      Inscribed by Roy to Vally Weigl, 1982 Sep 28.
      Accompanied by words as text, typescript photocopy; and ANS from Roy to Vally Weigl, 1982 Sep 28.
    - The spacious firmament on high: motet for double choir / W. K. Stanton; [text by] Joseph Addison. London: Oxford University Press, c1936., Stanton, Walter; 1 score (36 p.); 26 cm. (Box 22, Folder 557)
      The Oxford Choral Songs, no. 781.
      For two mixed choruses.
      Score includes piano part for rehearsal.
      Inscribed by Stanton to Weigl.
    - Songs of Travel. Part 1 / by Robert Louis Stevenson; set to music by Ralph Vaughan Williams., Vaughan Williams, Ralph, 1872-1958; 1 score (15, [1] p.); 27 cm. (Box 22, Folder 558)
      Low voice.
      London: Boosey & Co., c1933.
      Cover title.
      Includes words as text.
    - [Siegfried-Idyll] München: Drei Masken Verlag, 1923., Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883; 1 score (39 p.); 18 x 27 cm. (Box 22, Folder 559)
      Facsimile of the composer's holograph.
      Title from colophon.
    - [Burlesques, violoncello, piano] Old time burlesque: for violoncello and piano / Vally Weigl., Weigl, Vally, 1894-1982; 1 manuscript score (5 p.); 34 cm. (Box 22, Folder 560)
      Undated copyist's manuscript.
      Title changed from "Burlesque."
    - Zauber- und Segenssprüche: madrigale für fünf Stimmen a cappella: op. 10/1 / Florian Wiefler; [text by] Werner Bergengruen. Wien: Musikverlage Ludwig Krenn, 1960., Wiefler, Florian; 1 score (24 p.); 31 cm. (Box 22, Folder 561)
      Musik aus der Steiermark, Heft 12 / Steirischen Tonkünsterbund.
      Includes series and biographical information.
      Publisher's no.: L. K. 111.
      Inscribed by Wiefler to Vally Weigl, 1962 Feb.
- Correspondence, Series II
  This series consists chiefly of incoming letters, arranged alphabetically by name, with a small amount of outgoing carbons interfiled. While most correspondence dates from Weigl's years in the United States, a significant number of earlier letters are also present. Much of the correspondence concerns Weigl's music, collaboration with performers, and, particularly in the United States, his teaching positions, efforts to secure performances of his music, and specific performances. Letters dating from the period of the Weigl family's emigration document Karl and Vally's search for legal sponsorship and employment, including correspondence with a network of former students and other musicians, philanthropists, and refugee organizations. Also dating from this period are a large number of letters answering an invitation to a private concert of Weigl's music given in New York City in April, 1939.
  Notable correspondents include: Guido Adler, Willem Andriessen, Ernst Bacon, E. Power Biggs, Julius Bittner, Artur Bodanzky, Mary Louise Curtis Bok, Adolf Busch, Pablo Casals, Aaron Copland, Alfred Einstein, Emanuel Feuermann, Andor Földes, Ignaz Friedmann, Wilhelm Furtwängler, Rudolf Ganz, Robert Heger, Myra Hess, Ira Arthur Hirschmann, Bronislaw Huberman, Frederick Jacobi, Alexander Kipnis, Erich Kleiber, Otto Klemperer, Erich Korngold, Serge Koussevitsky, Thomas Mann, Clara Damrosch Mannes, Joseph Marx, Oskar Nedbal, William Primrose, Max Reger, Robert H. Schauffler, Heinrich Schenker, Arnold Schoenberg, Elisabeth Schumann, Rudolf Serkin, Otto Siegl, Fritz Stiedry, George Szell, Joseph Szigeti, Frederic Waldman, Bruno Walter, Felix Weingartner, Roy Dickinson Welch, Sylvia Spencer Welch, Paul Wittgenstein, and Alexander Zemlinsky. Some correspondents wrote letters of testimonial which Weigl reproduced and used in publicity. Transcribed or photocopied testimonial letters are present from Artur Bodanzky, John Erskine, Arnold Schoenberg, Rudolf Serkin, and Richard Strauss.
  Also present are family letters of Karl and Vally Weigl, particularly correspondence with Maria and Gerhart Piers, John and Etta Ruth Weigl, and photocopies of letters from Karl to Vally, 1943-1948, most written during a visit to Maria and Gerhart in 1945. Letters to Vally Weigl dating from before Karl Weigl's death are interfiled in this series. Most of these relate to family matters or their shared musical and social lives; a few concern Vally Weigl's music, including letters to her from Lukas Foss and Marian MacDowell. Correspondence of Vally Weigl dating after Karl's death is located in Series IX (Vally Weigl Papers). Correspondents found in both series are cross-referenced.
  - Adams, Helen S., 1938-1939; 3 items. (Box 22, Folder 562)
  - Adler, Guido, 1915 Nov. 16; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 563)
  - Adler, Peter Herman, 1942 Jun. 10; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 564)
  - Alphin, Albert, 1946-1948; 4 items. (Box 22, Folder 565)
  - American Committee for Christian Refugees, 1941 Jun. 8; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 566)
    See also Day, Helen
  - American Composers Alliance, 1944, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 567)
    See also Vally Weigl Correspondence
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1941 May 21; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 568)
  - American Theatre Wing, 1947-1949; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 569)
  - Andriessen, Willem, 1936-1937; 4 items. (Box 22, Folder 570)
  - Bach, David Josef, 1929 Nov. 18; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 571)
  - Bacon, Ernst, 1927-1947; 3 items. (Box 22, Folder 572)
  - Baldwin School (Bryn Mawr, Pa.), 1939 Mar. 6; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 573)
  - Baller, Edith, 1948 Apr. 27; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 574)
  - Bamberger, Carl, 1938 May 10; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 575)
  - Bass, Agnes, [1939] Apr. 11; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 576)
  - Bauer, Marion, 1939 Apr. 11; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 577)
  - Bennington College, 1938 Jul. 19; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 578)
  - Berkley, Harold, 1939 Feb. 18; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 579)
  - Berkowitz, Jacob
    See Germantown Friends School (Germantown, PA)
  - Betti, Adolfo, n. y. May 25; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 580)
  - Biggs, E. Power, 1948 Mar. 17; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 581)
  - Bittner, Julius, 1932-1937; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 582)
  - Bodanzky, Artur, 1935-1939, n.d.; 6 items. (Box 22, Folder 583)
    Includes transcript of letter from Roy Dickinson Welch
  - Boergermann, P. H., n. d.; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 584)
  - Bok, Mary Louise Curtis, 1939 Mar. 14; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 585)
  - Boston Conservatory of Music
    See Alphin, Albert
  - Boult, Adrian, Sir, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 586)
  - [Braunfels?], Walter, [1926?] May 22; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 586a)
  - Brinton, Elizabeth, 1941 May 16; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 587)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1934-1937; 5 items. (Box 22, Folder 588)
  - Brooklyn College, 1939 Feb. 7; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 589)
    See also Hopper, Franklin F.
    See also Lieberman, Maurice
  - Brosa, Antonio, 1938 Sep 2; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 590)
    Written by his wife
  - Brunswick, Mark, 1939 Apr. 17; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 591)
  - Busch, Adolf, 1929-1934; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 592)
  - Busch, Fritz, 1926-1934; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 593)
  - Byk, Richard, 1938, n. y.; 3 items. (Box 22, Folder 594)
  - Casals, Pablo, 1934-1935; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 595)
  - Chester County Art Association (PA)
    See Whitney, George Gillett
  - Chicago Musical College
    See Ganz, Rudolf
  - Children's Book Agency, 1933 Nov. 20; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 596)
  - Christie, Audrey Mildmay, 1937 Jun.-Jul.; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 597)
  - Christie, John, 1935 Apr. 20; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 598)
  - Coffin, Eva Proudfoot, 1943 Feb. 9; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 599)
  - Collins, Miss, 1936 Oct. 7; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 600)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System, Inc., 1939 Apr. 11; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 601)
  - Columbia University Teachers College
    See Dykema, Peter W.
  - Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1940 Jan. 17; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 602)
  - Cooper, Elizabeth M., 1939 Feb. 12; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 603)
    From "Marjorie"
  - Copland, Aaron, 1939 Apr 15; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 604)
  - Cornelis, Evert, 1926 Mar. 3; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 605)
  - Curtis Institute of Music
    See Bok, Mary Louise Curtis
  - Damrosch, Walter, 1939 Apr. 12; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 606)
  - Darkow, Marguerite D., 1939 Apr. 16; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 607)
  - Day, Helen, 1939 Apr. 14; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 608)
  - Daykarhanova Tamara, 1939 Apr. 11; 1 item. (Box 22, Folder 609)
  - Dessoff, Mrs., 1935; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 610)
  - De Villiers, Vera, 1936-1938; 2 items. (Box 22, Folder 611)
  - de Wetter, Louise, [1939 Apr. 14]; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 612)
  - Dobrowen, Issay, 1937 Jan. 24; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 613)
  - Dykema, Peter W., 1939 Feb.-Apr.; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 614)
  - Eastman School of Music, 1938 May 20; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 615)
  - Edward B. Marks Music Corporation, 1948 Feb. 17; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 616)
  - Egon Fleischel & Co., 1915 Sep 3; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 617)
  - Einstein, Alfred, 1929, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 618)
    One letter is a photocopy
  - Eisenberger, Severin, 1942 Dec 3; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 619)
  - Eitner, Kitty, 1937 Dec.; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 620)
  - Emergency Committee for Displaced Foreign Scholars
    See Lieberman, Maurice
  - Engel, Lehman, 1939 Feb.-Apr.; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 621)
  - Epstein, Julius, 1910-1911; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 622)
  - Erskine, John, 1939 Mar.-May; 5 items. (Box 23, Folder 623)
  - Fabricius, Ruth, [1937] Sep. 27; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 623a)
  - Fainsbert, Maurice
    See Musical Courier
  - Feuermann, Emanuel, 1941 Feb. 13; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 624)
  - Ffrangcon-Davies, Marjorie, 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 625)
  - Ficker, Rudolf, 1930 Mar. 8; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 626)
  - Földes, Andor, 1940 Aug. 6; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 627)
  - Foll, Ferdinand, 1912-1914, n.d.; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 628)
  - Foss, Lukas, 1945 Jul. 12-30; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 629)
  - Franckenstein, George, Sir, 1937 Dec. 31; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 630)
  - Franco, Johan, 1938 Dec. 20; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 631)
  - Frankl, Paul Josef, 1947-1948; 7 items. (Box 23, Folder 632)
  - Friedmann, Ignaz, 1931-1936, n.d.; 15 items. (Box 23, Folder 633)
  - Friends of Refugee Teachers, 1939 Feb. 15; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 634)
  - Fuchs, Hilde, 1939 Apr. 16; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 634a)
  - Fürst, Charlotte, [ca. 1902 Mar.]; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 635)
  - Furtwängler, Wilhelm, 1921-1929; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 636)
  - Ganz, Rudolf, 1938 May-Aug.; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 637)
  - Garabedian, Paul, 1948 Mar. 9; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 638)
  - Gartlan, George H., 1939 Apr. 10; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 639)
  - Germantown Friends School (Germantown, PA), 1943 May 27; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 640)
    2 transcripts
  - Gesellschaft der Musikfreunde in Wien, 1901-1930s; 4 items. (Box 23, Folder 641)
  - Gideonse, Harry D.
    See Hopper, Franklin F.
  - Glyndebourne Festival Opera House
    See Christie, John
  - Gotham School of Music (New York, N.Y.)
    See Garabedian, Paul
  - Grädener, Hermann, 1914 Jun.; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 642)
  - Grolle, Johan, 1939-1943; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 643)
  - Grünfeld, Alfred, 1912 Aug. 29; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 644)
  - Guinzburg, Mrs., 1941-1942; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 645)
  - Hambourg, Boris, 1938; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 646)
  - Hanna, Fräulein, 1938 Apr 30; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 647)
  - Hart House Quartet
    See Hambourg, Boris
  - Heger, Robert, 1927 Mar. 20; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 648)
  - Heitmann, Fritz, 1934 Jun. 18; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 649)
  - Hertz, Alfred
    See Hertz, Lilly
  - Hertz, Lilly, 1939 Jan. 4; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 650)
  - Hess, Myra, 1933-1939; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 651)
  - Hilb, Emil, 1939 Apr. 19; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 652)
  - Hirschman, Ira Arthur, 1938-1939; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 653)
  - Hoffmann, Rose, 1947-1948; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 654)
  - Högner, Friedrich, 1934 Jun.-Aug.; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 655)
  - Hopper, Franklin F., 1942 Dec 16; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 656)
  - Housman, Rosalie, n.y. Jun. 12; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 657)
  - Huberman, Bronislaw, 1932 Jul. 17; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 658)
  - Hull, Mrs., [1941]; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 659)
    English translation of "Campo Santo di Staglieno" from Gedichte, mixed voices, op. 7, on verso
  - Humby, Betty, 1934-1937; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 660)
  - Hüni-Mihacsek, Felicie, 1919-1925; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 661)
  - Infeld, Helen S. Adams
    See Adams, Helen S.
  - Jacobi, Frederick, 1936-1938; 5 items. (Box 23, Folder 662)
  - Jeans, Susi, n.y. Oct. 4; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 663)
  - Kalmus, Alfred, 1948 Feb. 18; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 664)
  - Kammerer, Paul, 1901-1912; 4 items. (Box 23, Folder 665)
  - Kempner, Kate, 1947-1949, n.y.; 6 items. (Box 23, Folder 666)
  - Kilenyi, Edward, 1941 Dec 22; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 667)
  - Kipnis, Alexander, 1942 Dec 12; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 668)
  - Klapper, Paul
    See Queens College
  - Kleiber, Erich, 1929-1931; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 669)
  - Klemperer, Otto, 1934-1938; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 670)
  - Kolisch, Rudolf, 1937 May 11; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 671)
  - Korn, Fannie Mayer, 1939 Apr. 10-12; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 672)
  - Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1938-1947; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 673)
  - Korngold, Julius, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 674)
  - Koussevitsky, Serge, 1939 Feb. 1; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 675)
  - Kraus, Lili, 1934 Jan 20; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 676)
  - Krueger, Karl, 1938 Jan.; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 677)
  - Kuh, Jennie C., 1938 Apr.-Jun.; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 678)
  - Kurt L. Schwarz, Old and Rare Books, Manuscripts, and Prints
    See Schwarz, Kurt L.
  - La Farge, Anne, n.y. Oct 5; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 679)
    To Toni Stolper
  - Lane, Rosalie, [1939 Apr. 13]; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 680)
  - Leiper, Henry Smith, 1943 May 28; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 681)
  - Lieberman, Maurice, 1943-1945; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 682)
  - List, Rudolf, 1947-1948; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 683)
  - Löwe, Ferdinand, 1910 Oct. 8; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 684)
  - Lowenthal, Eleanor, n.y. Aug. 25; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 685)
  - Lusterman, Don-David, 1947 Nov. 26; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 686)
  - Lyman, Janet, [1948 Jun. 17]; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 687)
  - Maar, Oskar, 1947-1948; 3 items. (Box 23, Folder 688)
  - McCollin, Frances, 1945 Sep 2; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 689)
  - MacDowell, Marian, 1945 Jul. 21-28; 2 items. (Box 23, Folder 690)
  - Mahler, Gustav, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 691)
    Photocopy
  - Malone, Margaret B., [1939 Jun. 5]; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 692)
  - Mandl, Richard, 1916 May 30; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 693)
  - Manerhofer, Carl, 1 item.
    See Mayerhofer, Carl
  - Mann, Thomas, 1939 Jan. 12; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 695)
  - Mannes, Clara, 1940 Jan. 16; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 696)
  - Marks Music Corporation
    See Edward B. Marks Music Corporation
  - Marshall, Lenore G., 1945 Jul. 30; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 697)
  - Marx, Joseph, 1947 Aug. 26; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 698)
  - Mayerhofer, Carl, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 694)
  - Messchaert, Joh. M. (Johannes Martinus), 1912 Oct; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 699)
  - Meyer, Marian W., 1939 Apr. 15; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 700)
  - Mischakoff, Mischa and Hortense, 1938 Dec. 25; 1 item. (Box 23, Folder 701)
  - Mitropoulos, Dmitri, 1948 Mar 26; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 702)
    Typed transcript
  - Morini, Erica, 1931 Jul 7; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 703)
  - Mortenson, Helga R., [1939?] Aug. 29; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 704)
  - Moulton, Dorothy, 1936-1937; 5 items. (Box 24, Folder 705)
  - Musical Courier, 1948 Feb.-Mar.; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 706)
  - NBC Artists Service, 1938 Jun. 17; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 707)
  - Nascimento, Ophelia do, 1937, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 708)
  - National Coordinating Committee for Aid to Refugees and Emigrants Coming from Germany, 1938 Jun. 27; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 709)
  - Naumburg, [Mrs. Edward S.], 1939 Apr. 9; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 710)
  - Nedbal, Oskar, 1908 Jun. 23; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 711)
  - New York Philharmonic
    See Hull, Mrs.
  - New York Public Library, 1942 Mar. 6; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 712)
  - Norden, N. Lindsay, 1939 Jan. 27; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 713)
  - Oberlaender Trust, 1944 Jun. 2; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 714)
  - Obrist, Aloys, 1910 Apr. 15; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 715)
  - Österreichische Creditanstalt-Wienerbankverein, 1938 Sep. 16; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 716)
  - Parma, Karl, 1947-1948; 5 items. (Box 24, Folder 717)
  - Perera, Ruth B., [1939 Apr. 18]; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 718)
  - Piers, Gerhart
    See Piers, Maria Weigl
  - Piers, Maria Weigl, 1941-1949, n.d.; 81 items. (Box 24, Folder 719-724)
  - Placement Committee for German and Austrian Musicians
    See Brunswick, Mark
  - Podolsky, Leo, 1938 May 23; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 725)
  - Pollitzer, Alice K., 1939 May 23; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 726)
  - Popper, Edith, 1938 Sep. 24; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 727)
  - Primrose, William, 1943 May 7; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 728)
  - Principe, Remy, 1935 Nov. 11; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 729)
  - Queens College (Flushing, N. Y.), 1939 Feb.-Apr.; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 730)
  - [Ramin?], Günter, 1934 Mar. 30; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 730a)
  - Reed, Helen Elizabeth, 1939 Mar. 12; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 731)
  - Reger, Max, 1909 Sep 18; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 732)
  - Renard, Rosita, 1937-1938; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 733)
  - Rodzinski, Artur, 1936-1938; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 734)
  - Rosenthal, Ada, 1947-1948; 4 items. (Box 24, Folder 735)
  - Rostal, Max, 1927-1931; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 736)
  - Rubenstein, Clara, 1938 Sep. 30; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 737)
  - Sanger, Eleanor N., [1939]; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 738)
  - Saunders, Silvia, [1939]; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 739)
  - Schalk, Franz, 1929 Sep. 19; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 739a)
  - Schauffler, Robert Haven, 1929 Nov. 3; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 740)
  - Scheider, Grete, 1947-1948; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 741)
  - Schenker, Heinrich, 1927-1934; 5 items. (Box 24, Folder 742)
  - Schnabel, Artur, 1938 Aug 27; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 743)
  - Schnitzler, Lilly, 1939 Apr. 19; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 744)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold, 1938, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 745)
    See also Ganz, Rudolf
  - Schreker, Franz, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 746)
  - Schrödter, Fritz, 1905 Feb 12; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 747)
  - Schultz, B., 1946 Oct. 20; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 748)
    Envelope only
  - Schumann, Elisabeth, 1937-1938; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 749)
  - Schuster, Joseph, 1935-1936; 3 items. (Box 24, Folder 750)
  - Schwarz, Kurt L., 1947 Sep. 29; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 751)
  - Schwarzbauer, Heribert, 1948 Apr. 1; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 752)
  - Seidel, Ina, 1915 Sep.-Nov.; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 752a)
    See also: Egon Fleischel & Co
  - Serkin, Rudolf, 1939-1945, n.d.; 6 items. (Box 24, Folder 753)
  - Settlement Music School (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    See Grolle, Johan
  - Sherwood Music School (Chicago, Ill.), 1938 Jun. 20; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 754)
    See also Podolsky, Leo
  - Siegel, Rudolf, 1928 May 12; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 755)
    Postcard photograph, possibly of Siegel
  - Siegl, Otto, 1930 Apr. 16; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 756)
  - Simpson, Miss, 1938 Mar 26; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 757)
  - Sinigaglia, Leone, 1933-1939; 2 items. (Box 24, Folder 758)
  - Smaill, Edith M., 1938 Jun. 18; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 759)
  - Smith, Carleton Sprague, [1939]; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 760)
  - Smith, Frederica, 1943 Jul. 28; 1 item. (Box 24, Folder 761)
  - Smith, Hamilton K., Mrs., 1942 Jan. 23; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 762)
  - Smith, Moses
    See Wachtell, Samuel R.
  - Spalding, Albert, 1947 Jun 5; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 763)
  - Spivacke, Harold, 1939 Jan. 17; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 764)
  - Staatlich genehmigte Gesellschaft zur Verwertung musikalischer Urheberrechte, 1939 Jan. 23; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 765)
    (STAGMA)
  - Sternberg, Daniel, 1947 Dec. 23; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 766)
  - Stiedry, Fritz, 1938 May-Sep.; 2 items. (Box 25, Folder 767)
  - Stock, Frederick, 1932-1937; 4 items. (Box 25, Folder 768)
  - Stolper, Toni, 1938-1948; 4 items. (Box 25, Folder 769)
    See also La Farge, Anne
  - Straube, Karl, 1926 Jan. 5; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 770)
  - Strauss, Richard, 1921 Mar. 12; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 771)
    Photocopy, with a typed transcript
  - Sunshine, Jesse S., 1949 Jun. 19; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 772)
  - Synnestvedt, Cara, 1943 Apr; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 773)
    With typed transcript
  - Szell, George, 1937 May 7; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 774)
  - Szigeti, Joseph, 1929 May 29; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 775)
  - Tanzer, Albert, 1938 Aug 29; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 776)
    See also Hirschman, I. A.
  - Tarnowsky, S., 1938 May 10; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 777)
  - Taubmann, Leo, 1943 Mar. 23; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 778)
  - Taylor, Davidson, 1939 Apr. 7; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 779)
  - Tedesko, [Mrs. Victor], 1947 Sep. 22; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 780)
  - Thorborg, Kerstin, 1936, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 25, Folder 781)
  - Timbres, Rebecca S. J., 1939 Apr. 16; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 782)
  - Toch, Lilly and Ernst, 1938 May-Jun.; 2 items. (Box 25, Folder 783)
  - Trump, Marjorie, 1939 Mar. 27; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 784)
  - Universal Edition
    See Kalmus, Alfred
  - Vassar College
    See Woodruff, Edith S.
  - Vehanen, Kosti, 1936 Nov. 28; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 785)
  - Vienna (Austria) Bürgermeister, 1924-1928; 2 items. (Box 25, Folder 786)
  - Volavy, Marguerite, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 25, Folder 787)
  - Wachtell, Samuel R., n.d.; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 788)
    To Moses Smith
  - Waldman, Frederic, 1945 Aug. 18; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 789)
  - Walter, Bruno, 193--1945; 5 items. (Box 25, Folder 790)
  - Walz, L. Humphrey, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 791)
  - Wandel, Louise, 1947 [Apr. 6]; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 792)
  - Warburg, Gerald F., 1939 Apr. 17; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 793)
  - Weidmann, -----, 1913 Sep. 22; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 793a)
  - Weightman-Smith, Michael, 1939 Apr. 18; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 794)
  - Weigl, Antonia, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 795)
  - Weigl, Etta Ruth Hoskins
    See Weigl, John
  - Weigl, John, 1945-1949, n.d.; 11 items. (Box 25, Folder 796)
  - Weigl, Vally, 1943-1948; 22 items. (Box 25, Folder 797)
  - Weingartner, Felix, 1912-[1913?]; 3 items. (Box 25, Folder 798)
  - Weiss, Aline P., [1939 Apr. 19]; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 799)
  - Welch, Roy Dickinson, 1932-1945; 4 items. (Box 25, Folder 800)
    See also Bodanzky, Artur